<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on niels van eck</title><link>https://nielsvaneck.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on niels van eck</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:01:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nielsvaneck.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>render-md-markdown, a GitHub Action</title><link>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-31-render-md-markdown-a-github-action/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:01:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-31-render-md-markdown-a-github-action/</guid><description>Earlier, I wrote about rendering Mermaid graphs in Markdown on GitHub by invoking a script, possibly using a make target to cover all Markdown files in an entire repository. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Mermaid diagrams and the script presented in that post in README.md docs for a couple of projects. While the script works great, having to remember to run it or plumb client side automation to do so automatically can be a bit of a hassle.</description></item><item><title>Rendering Mermaid graphs in Markdown on GitHub</title><link>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-20-rendering-mermaid-graphs-in-markdown-on-github/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 08:03:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-20-rendering-mermaid-graphs-in-markdown-on-github/</guid><description>When writing documentation for software, sooner or later you&amp;rsquo;re going to hit the point at which a picture will explain in a glance what you would have a hard time describing in the proverbial &amp;ldquo;thousand words&amp;rdquo;. While documenting something technical, this usually means diving into the drawing section of whatever editor you&amp;rsquo;re using and wrangling with lines and boxes until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied with your masterpiece or you&amp;rsquo;ve exhausted your patience with the tool.</description></item><item><title>Bye, Wordpress!</title><link>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-09-bye-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nielsvaneck.com/post/2021-01-09-bye-wordpress/</guid><description>Last summer, frustrated over the loss of my personal domain, I bought a cute url and set up a Wordpress blog with the intention of sharing some content about what I was working on. Our son was born around the same time and so the site sat idle for a few months, but when I picked up writing back in November, the experience with Wordpress irked me. Wordpress is a fine CMS, it is great for getting a quick blog up and going, but I wanted more control over my content.</description></item></channel></rss>